A Guide to the Clarence L. Townes Jr. Papers, 1944-1988
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Clarence L. Townes, Jr. Papers 1944-1988
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 293
23.4 linear feet
Clarence L. Townes, Jr.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions
Acquisition Information
The collection was a gift to Special Collections and Archives from Clarence L. Townes, Jr. in 1991.
Biographical/Historical Information
Clarence Lee Townes, Jr., businessman, political activist, and a significant participant in the revitalization of Richmond, Virginia, has spent much of his life working to broaden and increase economic and political opportunities for African-Americans in Virginia.
Born in Richmond on January 21, 1928, Townes is the son of Alice Smith and Clarence L. Townes, Sr. and graduated from Armstrong High School in 1944. Townes attended Virginia Union University and received a B.S. degree (Commerce). In 1951, he married Grace Elizabeth Harris of Richmond and the couple had four children. Commissioned in 1952 as a Second Lietenant in the United States Army Infantry, Townes received an honorabel discharge in 1953.
After the army, Townes was appointed Assistant Manager (Richmond Office) of the Virginia Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Company, a company his father had helped found. He later became director of training (1964- 1966).
Townes was active in Republican Party politics in the late 1950s. As many African-Americans were turning towards the Democratic Party, he served on the Richmond City Republican Committee (1958-1961) and as a board member of Richmond Forward, a political action group. Also, her served as commissioner (1963-1966) of the Richmond Redevelopment and Housing Authority. Townes attended the 1964 Republican convention as the first black member of a Virginia delegation in modern times. After the convention, he ran as the Republican Candidate for the Richmond-Henrico seat in the Virginia House of Delegates. Although he lost, and would not seek public office in the future, the election race brought national attention to the South and its treatment of African-Americans in the political process. "The great thing that came out of this (election), "Townes wrote at the time, "was to focus the attention of both parties on legitimately seeking the Negro vote (in Virginia)."
Townes was Special Assistant to the State Chairman, Republican Party of Virginia in 1965 (1965-1966). He organized and was treasurer of the National Negro Republican Assembley (1965-1966) which ran an eight man Republican slate against an eight man Democratic slate. In 1966, Townes became an Assistant to the Chairman of the Republican National Committee (1966-1970) and later Director of Minorities (1967-1970), working to increase Republican ties with minorities.
In 1970, after leaving the RNC, he helped found the Joint Center for Political Affairs, an African-American think-tank associated with Howard University. The Joint Center was created to help newly elected black officials with the business of government. Townes sereved as Director of Governmental Affairs (1970-1974).
In addition, Townes was a board and founding member of the Jefferson Townhouse Corporation of Richmond, Virginia, a black controlled enterprise that operated a housing complex located in the city. In 1970 he became a member of the Board of Directors of the Consolidated Bank and Trust Co. of Richmond, the oldest black controlled bank in the nation. Townes also worked as a consultant on federal programs to Virginia State College and was a consultant to the Virginia Electric and Power company on matters pertaining to equal employment. He was also a consultant for the Manpower Administration, U.S. Department of Labor, evaluating the agency's National Office Equal Opportunity Program.
After commuting by bus from Richmond to Washington, D.C. for eight years, Townes returned to Richmond in 1974 to establish a bus company called Metro Coach. After a series of business disappointments, lawsuits and investigations the company eventually turned into a success. At this time, the early 1980s, Townes chaired Richmond Renaissance, a non-profit, biracial corporation formed to foster economic development in downtown Richmond. Townes served as Richmond Renaissance's deputy director from 1982 until 1991 when he appointed director.
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes correspondence, notes, newspaper and journal clippings, various organizational minutes, numerous reports and files, drafts of speeches, manuscripts and published materials dating from 1944 through 1988. The bulk of the collection dates from the early 1960s through the mid 1980s and focuses on Townes' interest in and involvement with issues concerning race, politics, and the revitalization of downtown Richmond. The collection also includes a significant amount of material on the role of African-American Republicans in the Virginia Republican Party of the 1960s and in the National Republican Party during the late 1960s and early 1970s.
Related information on the revitalization and development of downtown Richmond can be found in the Richmond Renaissance Archives (M 303) and the McClenahan (M 302).
Series I contains materials documenting Townes' numerous entrepreneurial and civic activities, mostly dating from the late 1950s until the early 1960s. Miscellaneous material, which were not appropriate for other major sections of the collection, are also located within this series.
Series II contains the largest quantity of material and concerns the Virginia Republican Party (1963-1966) and the Republican National Committee (1966-1972). Correspondence, reports and publications, material from Townes' race for the Virginia General Assembly and his work with the National Negro Republican Assembly (1964-1966) are included in this series, in addition to miscellaneous Republican items.
Series III consists of records from Townes' work with the Joint Center for Political Studies, dating from the early 1970s.
Series IV is composed of materials generated by Townes as deputy director in the early years of the Richmond Renaissance. These records focus on projects, particularly Sixth Street Marketplace and the Richmond Metro Visitors Center.
Series V contains an abundant collection of publications and reports collected by Townes, many on urban and minority issues. The majority of the publications were distributed by the Republican Party (late 1960s-early 1970s). There are also U.S. government publications, publications from the Joint Center for Political Studies, and miscellaneous publications pertaining to business, education, localities, civic organizations and public policy organizations.
Series VI is comprised of ephemeral material, primarily related to the Republican Party, as well as tapes of speeches, business cards, address books and business calendars. This series also contains nearly forty photographs of Townes (including photos of Townes with Martin Luther King and national political leaders) and others. Most of the photographs were taken for publicity, dating from his campaign for the General Assembly in 1965 through his days at the Republican National Committee in the late 1960s and early 1970s.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Materials have been separated into six series and arranged alphabetically and chronologically therein.
Organization
Series I--Business/Civic Work/Miscellaneous (n.d., 1961-1972)
Series II--Republican Party, Subseries A: Virginia (1948-1970), Subseries B: Third Congressional District (n.d., 1963-1965),Subseries C: National negro Republican Assembly (n.d., 1964-1966), Subseries D: Republican National Committee (n.d., 1965-1970), Subseries E: Miscellaneous (n.d., 1957-1972)
Series III--Joint Center for Political Studies (1970-1976)
Series IV--Richmond Renaissance (n.d., 1982-1987)
Series V--Publications (n.d., 1961-1973)
Series VI--Ephemera and photographs (n.d., 1940s-1970s)
Contents List
- Business/Civic Work/Miscellaneous 1961-1972
  - Commission on Community Relations (Richmond) n.d. (Box 1)
  - Community Development Revenue Sharing (Block Grants) Workshop, December 1972 (Box 1)
  - Consolidated Band and Trust Co. 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Council on Economic Education in Virginia 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Economic Development and Manpower (report used by Manpower Commission study?) (Box 1)
  - Jefferson Townhouse-Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous Material n.d. 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Jefferson Townhouse Corporation 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - La Salle, The-Lease Agreement 1966 (Box 2)
  - NAACP 58th Annual Convention, Miscellaneous Convention Material 1967 (Box 2)
  - Obituary of Clarence L. Townes, Sr. (Box 2)
  - Phi Beta Lambda-Correspondence 1964-1973 (Box 2)
  - Quality Printing Company 1964 (Box 2)
  - Richmond Area Community Council-Correspondence, Reports, Miscellaneous Material n.d. 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Richmond Area Heart Association-Correspondence, Minutes, Miscellaneous Publications 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Richmond Redevelopment and Housing Authority-Correspondence, Reports n.d. 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - Richmond Redevelopment and Housing Authority-Correspondence, Reports, Miscellaneous Material n.d. 1963-1966 (Box 3)
  - Richmond Sports Club, Inc. 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Richmond Urban League-Community Service Award (Mrs. Grace H. Townes) 1961 (Box 3)
  - United Givers Fund of Richmond, Henrico, Chesterfield, Inc. 1963-1966 (Box 3)
  - Virginia Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Co. Training material, correspondence n.d. 1962, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Virginia State University 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Virginia Union University-Centennial Campaign 1965-1966 (Box 3)
- Republican Party 1948-1972
  - Virginia 1948-1970
    - Correspondence (Poll tax related), Virginia on New Republican minutes, Richmond News-Leader Editorial on Negro Voting 1948, 1957, 1959 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, AFL-CIO Questionaire for State Elections and Misc. n.d. 1964, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, Publications, and Miscellaneous Material n.d. 1964, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, Publications, and Miscellaneous Material n.d. 1964-1966 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, Publications, and Miscellaneous Material n.d. 1965 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, publications, and Miscellaneous material 1966 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (congratulations cards, etc. to Townes on appointment as assistant to state chairman) 1965 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, speeches, notes n.d. 1964-1966 (Box 4)
    - Election Profile 1970 (Box 4)
    - Letter by Townes to Dean of Harvard Business School 1966 (Box 4)
  - Third Congressional District n.d. 1963-1965
    - Analysis of 1965 General Assembly Race by Townes n.d. 1965 (Box 5)
    - Campaign for General Assembly-Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Speeches, Miscellaneous Publications n.d. (1 of 3) 1965 (Box 5)
    - Campaign for General Assembly-Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Speeches, Miscellaneous Publications n.d. (2 of 3) 1965 (Box 5)
    - Campaign for General Assembly-Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Speeches, Miscellaneous Publications n.d. (3 of 3) 1965 (Box 5)
    - Campaign for General Assembly-Draft of letter by Townes on loss of Election 1965 (Box 5)
    - Campaign for General Assembly-Virginia Education Association Matierial 1965 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence n.d. 1964-1965 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, Campaign material, Newspaper Clippings, Speeches 1965 (Box 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings, Newsletters, Reports, Speeches, Campaign Material, Miscellaneous n.d. 1965 (Box 6)
    - Precinct Worker Lists and Instructions n.d. 1963-1964 (Box 6)
    - Richmond Forward 1964 (Box 6)
  - National Negro Republican Assembly n.d. 1964-1966
    - Correspondence, By-Laws, Reports n.d. 1964 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Newspaper Clippings 1965 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings 1966 (Box 7)
  - Republican National Committee n.d. 1965-1970
    - Art Fletcher-correspondence 1969 (Box 7)
    - Biographical Sketches, Resume of Clarence Townes n.d. 1967, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Black Media-Lists of publishers, Newspaper Clippings, Reports n.d. 1966-1968 (Box 7)
    - Black Vote-Reports, Miscellaneous Material 1966 (Box 7)
    - Board for Fundamental Education 1970 (Box 7)
    - California politics, Black support of Republican Party, Black Panthers, Newspaper Clippings 1968 (Box 7)
    - Campaign Plan 1969-Holton for Governor of Virginia, GOP Report on Race 1969 (Box 7)
    - Civil Rights Record, Research Report by RNC 1965 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence-Alexander, Lamar (legislative assistant to Howard Baker) 1967 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Press Releases 1966 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, Press Releases, Reports 1967 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, Press Releases, Reports, Miscellaneous 1968 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (form letters) 1968-1969 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Reports 1969 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, Publications, notes 1968-1970 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Notes, Miscellaneous n.d. 1969 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, News Clippings 1970 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (from Townes) January-February 1970 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (from Townes) March 1970 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (from Townes) April-May 1970 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (from Townes) June-August 1970 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence-Telegrams Sent 1968-1969 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence (Regarding Blacks in State Governments) 1970 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, Bhite House 1969-1970 (Box 9)
    - Convention 1968-Campaign Material, Agendas, Newspaper Clippings, Ephemera 1968 (Box 9)
    - Field Reports Regarding State Politics, Black Participation in Republican Party (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1968 (Box 9)
    - Forward Together Election Analysis: 1968 and the Black American Voter, report by Minorities Division, Clarence L. Townes, Jr. Director January 1969 (Box 9)
    - List of Black Office Holders and Miscellaneous lists n.d. (Box 9)
    - Lists of Blacks Serving in Nixon Administration n.d. (Box 9)
    - Mailing Lists n.d. 1967 (Box 10)
    - Mailing Lists (computer)-Black Monitor News (Box 10)
    - Mailing Lists (computer)-Newspaper and Periodicals (Box 10)
    - Mailing Lists (computer)-Negro Weekly Magazines (Box 10)
    - Mailing Lists (computer)-Negro General Mailing List (Box 10)
    - Mailing Lists (computer)-Other (Box 10)
    - Management Committee n.d. 1967, 1969 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous n.d. 1968 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Notes n.d. (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Speeches, Newspaper Clippings and Publications on the Negro in the United States n.d. 1967-1968 (Box 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1965-1971 (Box 11)
    - Negro Appointees-Statewide n.d. (Box 11)
    - Negro Delegates to Republican National Convention 1968 (Box 11)
    - The Observer and Equal Opportunity publications 1970 (Box 11)
    - Pacifica Radio n.d. 1970 (Box 11)
    - Phi Beta Sigma 1969 (Box 11)
    - Presidential Inauguration 1969 (Box 11)
    - Press Releases, Newspaper Clippings n.d. 1969-1970 (Box 12)
    - Proposal to Clarence Townes from Alfred Duckett concerning the Nixon Administration and the Black Community 1970 (Box 12)
    - Reports n.d. 1966, 1969-1970 (Box 12)
    - Speeches by Townes 1966-1969 (Box 12)
    - Talent Search 1969 (Box 12)
    - Virginia Visit 1969 (Box 12)
    - White House Press Releases on Urban Affairs 1969 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous n.d. 1957-1972
    - Analysis of Presidential Primaries-Newspaper Clippings, Reports 1972 (Box 13)
    - Chicago, Illinois area Republican Activity-letter from Sen. Everett Dirksen, Miscellaneous Materia n.d. 1957 (Box 13)
    - Christmas Card from Richard M. Nixon Family n.d. (Box 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1965-1971 (Box 13)
    - Newspaper, Periodical Articles on Townes n.d. 1960s (Box 13)
    - Report on Minority Representation and Congressional Districts n.d. (Box 13)
    - Speeches-No Identified Author, (Townes speeches) n.d. 1965-1970 (Box 13)
    - Speeches by Townes n.d. (Box 13)
    - Speeches-Lincoln Material (Box 13)
    - Speeches-Miscellaneous Speeches by Others (Box 13)
- Joint Center for Political Studies 1970-1976
  - Board of Governors Meeting, Minutes, Reports 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Reports n.d. 1971-1974 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Reports, Various Publications n.d. 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Reports, Biographical Sketch of Townes, Maps of Chesterfield County n.d. 1974 (Box 14)
  - EEO Report-Correspondence, Notes 1970-1971 (Box 14)
  - EEO Report by Townes-Analysis of Department of Labor's Manpower 1970, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Government Publication on Civil Rights Act; Remarks of President Johnson at Howard University 1965 (Box 15)
  - Meeting, February 2-3, 1973 Education and Special Projects Report February 2-3, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Minority Contractors n.d. 1971 (Box 15)
  - National League of Cities-Correspondence, Reports 1976 (Box 15)
  - National League of Cities-Reports 1976 (Box 15)
  - Report on Comprehensive Planning and Development Contract-(National Urban Coalition, Department of Housing and Urban Development) 1972 (Box 15)
  - Status Report by the Executive Director-July 1970 (Box 15)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights-Articles on Federal Civil Rights Enforcement-October 1970 (Box 15)
- Richmond Renaissance 1982-1987
  - Air Reservist-Official Magazine of the Air National Guard and Air Force Reserve March/April 1984 (Box 16)
  - Articles of Incorporation, By-Laws, Statement of Goals 1983 (Box 16)
  - Awareness and Attitudes Toward The Richmond Metro Chamber-Research Report to Metropolitan Richmond Chamber of Commerce-Southeastern Institute of Research, Inc 1983 (Box 16)
  - Blues Armory Project-A Preliminary Planning and Development Study 1985 (Box 16)
  - Board of Directors, Executive Committee-Minutes, Agendas 1982 (Box 16)
  - Board of Directors, Executive Committee, Liaison Committee-Minutes, Agendas 1983 (Box 16)
  - Board of Directors, Executive Committee-Minutes, Agendas 1984 (Box 16)
  - Broad Street Cinema Task Force March 30, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Broad Street Committee 1983 (Box 16)
  - Brown's Island-Scope of Services n.d. (Box 16)
  - Brown's Island Walkway n.d. 1983, Oversize (Box 16)
  - Budget/Contract with City of Richmond-Correspondence, Notes 1983, Oversize (Box 16)
  - Captial City Government Commission 1981 (Box 16)
  - Capital Region Airport Commission-Golden Wings Over Richmond 1977 (Box 16)
  - City of Richmond-First year Comprehensive Plan n.d. 1970 (Box 16)
  - City Strategy Team n.d. 1982 (Box 16)
  - City Strategy Team, Mid-Year Status Report 1981 (Box 17)
  - CLC Taskforce n.d., 1983, Oversize (Box 17)
  - Continental Cablevision Film: Richmond 1986 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence Memorandum from Moore to Dean, Townes regarding Jim Rouse's ideas on Richmond Renaissance's Executive Director 1982 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence To Philip M. Hawley, William B. Thalhimer, Jr from Charles Robb n.d. (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous n.d., March-April 1982 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous May-December 1982 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous n.d. January 1983 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous February-March 1983 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous May-August 1983 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous October-December 1983 1983 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Notes Miscellaneous n.d. January-March 1984 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous April-November 1984 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous 1985 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous n.d., January-March 1986 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Notes, Miscellaneous April-November 1986 (Box 19)
  - Cultural Loop Trolley press kit 1986-1987 (Box 19)
  - District of Columbia Tourism Development Policy Study-Office of Business and Economic Development, Government of the District of Columbia-Report July 1981 (Box 19)
  - Economic Profile-Richmond, Virginia City of Richmond's Economic Development Office 1981 (Box 19)
  - Glenn Monigle and Associates, Inc.-Richmond XXI Project-Reports (Box 19)
  - Interim Report of the Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission on Local Mandates and Financial Resources to the Governor and the General Assembly of Virginia 1983 (Box 19)
  - Jackson Ward Development Strategy-A Proposal from Thomas and Means Associates 1987 (Box 19)
  - Liaison Committee 1982 (Box 19)
  - Mailing Lists 1985 (Box 20)
  - McGuire, Woods, Battle and Boothe-Richmond Still Making History-Service Mark 1987, Oversize (Box 20)
  - Meeting of Incorporators, Articles of Incorporation, Goals n.d. 1982 (Box 20)
  - Metro Richmond Visitors Center-John D. Hunt Correspondence, notes, Reports 1985 (Box 20)
  - Metro Richmond Visitors Center-John D. Hunt Correspondence, notes, Reports 1985 (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous n.d.(1 of 2) (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous n.d. (2 of 2) (Box 20)
  - Monigle Report on Richmond-Glenn Monigle and Associates, Inc. (Box 20)
  - Name/Place Cards Townes, West Deese, Evans and others unidentified event n.d. (Box 21)
  - Newspaper Articles on Richmond Renaissance- Richmond Times Dispatch, Richmond Newsleader 1982, Oversize (Box 21)
  - Office Equipment Fliers n.d. (Box 21)
  - Project One Design Coordination Meeting-Minutes n.d. (Box 21)
  - Public Relations Institute, Inc.-Proposal for a Public Relations Program for Richmond, Correspondence 1983 (Box 21)
  - Renaissance Canal Walk-Advertisement Prototype n.d. (Box 21)
  - Revitalization News v. 6, n. 4 Fall 1988 (Box 21)
  - Richmond Arts District Association-Community Development Block Grant Funding n.d. 1981 (Box 21)
  - Richmond Banner Display Program 1986, Oversize (Box 21)
  - Richmond Convention and Visitors Bureau-Correspondence, 1984, 1994 (Box 21)
  - Richmond Education Association-Fliers Attacking City Manager and Proposed School Budget n.d. (Box 21)
  - Richmond Renaissance: A New Cooperative Spirit Notes, Revisions n.d. (Box 21)
  - Richmond Renaissance Employee Guidlines n.d. (Box 21)
  - Richmond Renaissance-Meeting of Incorporation, Guidelines for Staffing, By-Laws n.d. 1982 (Box 21)
  - Richmond XXI Committee 1987 (Box 21)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Cochran, Stephenson and Donkervoet, Inc. Architects-drawings n.d (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Correspondence 1982-1984 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Enterprise Development Co.-Correspondence, Report and Analysis of Project n.d. 1982, 1983 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Enterprise Development, Inc.-Model I, Model II, Model II-financial plans n.d. (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Financial/Legal matters-Correspondence 1983 (Box 22)
  - Financial/Legal Matters-Cost Estimates, Miscellaneous n.d. 1983 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Grand Opening-Marketing Plan 1985 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Grand Opening-Ten Day Event Schedule 1985 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Ground Breaking (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Budget, Timetable n.d. 1984 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Correspondence Federal Grant for Project 1984 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Newspaper articles on event 1984 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Platform seating, luncheon, Miscellaneous notes n.d. 1984 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Practical Protocol Guide Governor's Office 1977 (Box 22)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Ground Breaking-Invitations 1984 (Box 23)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Ground Breaking-Invitations, Addresses, Notes 1984 (Box 23)
  - 6th Street Marketplace-Ground Breaking-Invitation List 1984 (Box 23)
  - Marcellus Wright Cox and Smith Architects-Correspondence; Drawings, Sketches n.d. November 16, 1982 (Box 23)